TYLER POLAND

Austin, TX 78681 · 720.469.5016 poland.tyler@gmail.com · http://tylerpoland.io

Experienced software engineer with a demonstrated history across a breadth of industries. Forever a knowledge-hungry journeyman with a predilection for strong software craftsmanship and experience in both frontend and backend development.

EXPERIENCE

JAN 2020 - CURRENT

IOS ENGINEER, APPLE

Technologies: Swift, Objective-C, Internal tooling, Xcode, Git

Build, test, and ship internal iOS apps.

AUG 2018 – CURRENT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, OUTDOORSY

Technologies: Swift, Fastlane, Kotlin, Golang, CircleCI, Bitrise, Git, Postgres

Build, test, and ship Android and iOS features for multi-tenant marketplace application in the vacation rental and outdoor experience industry.

FEB 2016 - AUG 2018

IOS & WEB ENGINEER, AETNA

Technologies: Swift, XCTest, Jenkins, Xcode Server, Fastlane, Angular, Node.js, Git

Build, test, and ship feature code that enables users to live healthier lives.

NOV 2015 - FEB 2016

IOS ENGINEER, AETNA MEMBER CENTRAL

Technologies: Node.js, React Native, Objective-C, Swift, AWS, Git

Provided POCs and features in both React Native and Swift while rewriting Member Central app in Swift. Also rearchitected the app to use a standard MVC approach.

APR 2014 - NOV 2015

SDET (TEST ENGINEER), ITRIAGE

Technologies: Ruby, Calabash, Jenkins, Sauce labs, Git

Designed and implemented automated and manual tests / processes in support of the iTriage application. Write API and UI tests to ensure quality.

APR 2011 - APR 2014

QA ENGINEER, ACCURENCE

Stack: Ruby, Calabash, Jenkins, Sauce labs, Git

Implemented strong quality processes and began automating repetitive tasks. Reduced escape defect metric by roughly 70%.

EDUCATION

MAY 2011

B.A. ECONOMICS, VALPARAISO UNIVERSITY

Certifications: IT Fellow (Help Desk and Network)

LEADERSHIP / MISC

MAR 2019 - PRESENT

ORGANIZER, AUSTIN ALGORITHMS MEETUP